393 Huaxia St. · Pudong, Shanghai · (+86) 18621772305 · xuyy2@shanghaitech.edu.cn · MainPage

Research Interests I am interested in computer vision and deep learning, especially human-centric tasks in image or video, including visual attention prediction, pedestrian trajectory prediction, pose estimation and dancing to music.

EDUCATION

ShanghaiTech University, Shanghai, China Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science

National University of Singapore, Singapore

Visiting Ph.D student

Dalian University of Technology, Dalian, China

B.Eng. in Network Engineering

Sep. 2015 - Present Advisor: Dr. Shenghua Gao Aug. 2019 - Jan. 2020 Advisor: Dr. Jiashi Fenq Sep. 2011 - Jul. 2015 GPA: 89.7/100

Papers

Conference Yanyu Xu, Yanbing Dong, Junru Wu, Zhengzhong Sun, Zhiru Shi, Jingyi Yu and Shenghua Gao: "Gaze Prediction in Dynamic 360° Immersive Videos", IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2018.

> Yanyu Xu*, Zhixin Piao*, and Shenghua Gao: "Encoding Crowd Interaction with Deep Neural Network for Pedestrian Trajectory Prediction", IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2018. [* indicates equal contribution]

> Ziheng Zhang*, Yanyu Xu*, Jinyi Yu, and Shenghua Gao, "Saliency Detection in 360° Videos", European Conference on Computer Vision, (ECCV), 2018. [* indicates equal contribution]

> Quan Chen, Tiezheng Ge, Yanyu Xu, Zhiqiang Zhang, and Kun Gai, "Human Semantic Matting", ACM International Conference on Multimedia (ACM MM), 2018.

Yanyu Xu, Nianyi Li, Junru Wu, Jingyi Yu, and Shenghua Gao, "Beyond Universal Saliency: Personalized Saliency Prediction with Multi-task CNN", In Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2017. (Outstanding Student Paper Runner-up).

Yanyu Xu, Shenghua Gao: "Bi-Level Multi-Column Convolutional Neural Networks for Facial Landmark Point Detection", European Conference on Computer Vision Workshop, (ECCVW) 2016.

Journal Papers

Yanyu Xu, Shenghua Gao, Junru Wu, Nianyi Li and Jingyi Yu, "Beyond Universal Saliency: Personalized Saliency and its Prediction", IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI). (Accepted)

Yanyu Xu, Zhixin Piao, Wen Liu, Ziheng Zhang, Jingyi Yu, and Shenghua Gao: "SUNNet: A Novel Framework for Simultaneous Human Parsing and Pose Estimation", Neurocomputing. (Accepted)

Papers in Submission

Yanyu Xu, Zhixin Piao, Peiyao Wang, Jiashi Feng and Shenghua Gao: "DancingPose: A Simple Model for for Predicting Dancing Pose Sequence from Music". (CVPR 2020 Under review)

Lei Jin*, Yanyu Xu*, Jia Zheng, Jingyi Yu and Shenghua Gao: "Geometric Structure Based and Regularized Depth Estimation From 360° Indoor Imagery". (CVPR 2020 Under review)

Peiyao Wang, Yanyu Xu, Weixin Luo and Shenghua Gao: "SIRI-SDR: SpatIal Relation Induced Spatial Description Resolution". (CVPR 2020 Under review)

Yanyu Xu, Yingying Zhang, Zhengxin Li, Desen Zhou, Siqin Chen, Yi Ma and Shenghua Gao, "Multicolumn CNN and its Applications for Crowd Counting and Face Alignment", International Journal of Computer Vision (TIP). (Under review)

Yanyu Xu, Ziheng Zhang, and Shenghua Gao, "Spherical CNNs for Saliency Detection and Gaze Prediction in 360° Videos", IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI). (Under review)

Yanyu Xu, and Shenghua Gao, "Saliency Detection with Visual and Auditory Information in 360° Videos", IEEE Signal Processing Letters. (Under review)

Teaching

Teaching Assistant at ShanghaiTech University for:

EXPERIENCE

• Computer Vision II, Spring 2017

• Deep Learning, Fall 2016

Internship Alimama Department, the Alibaba Group

Experience Research Intern

Instructor: Dr. Shenghua Gao

Mar. 2018 - Sep. 2018 Advisor: Dr. Tiezheng Ge

Instructor: Dr. Yi Ma

PROJECT EXPERIENCE Personalized Saliency and its Prediction

Aug. 2016 - Sep. 2017

- We propose the first work that considers the personalized saliency.
 - We design two models that decomposes a PSM into the combination of USM and discrepancy map between the PSM and USM, including a multi-task CNN framework and a multi-task CNN framework

Spherical CNNs for Saliency Detection and Gaze Prediction in 360° Videos Jan. 2018 - Mar. 2019

- We define some new spherical operations including spherical convolution, spherical pooling, spherical ConvLSTM cell and spherical MSE loss to deal with the distortion problem for panoramic data.
- Our proposed spherical operations are more natural and useful for human visual attention prediction tasks *i.e.* saliency detection and gaze prediction in 360° videos.

Talks

DancingPose: A Simple Model for for Predicting Dancing Pose Sequence from Music Invited talk at NUS LV Lab seminar, Dec. 2019.

Dancing Pose: A Simple Model for for Predicting Dancing Pose Sequence from Music Invited talk at Huawei-NUS Advanced Deep Learning Forum, Nov. 2019.

Beyond Universal Saliency Detection

Invited talk at CS Department, Shanghai University, Nov. 2018.

Professional Conference reviewer: CVPR2019, ICCV2019, AAAI2019, CVPR2020, ECCV2020.

SERVICES **Journal reviewer**: IEEE TIP, TCSVT, NeuroComputing.

SKILLS Python, MATLAB, C++, Caffe, PyTorch, Tensorflow, LATEX

Awards

- Nomination Award of the 2018 Microsoft Research Asia Fellowship
- National Scholarship for Doctoral Students 2018
- Outstanding Student of ShanghaiTech University, 2018 2019
- Finalist, Outstanding Student Paper Runner-up of IJCAI 2017
- China National Post-Graduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling, Third Prize, 2017
- Outstanding Student of ShanghaiTech University, 2016 2017
- Outstanding Student of ShanghaiTech University, 2015 2016

REFERENCES Shenghua Gao

Assistant Professor Phone: +(86)185-2105-2610

School of Information Science and Technology

ShanghaiTech Univeristy E-mail: gaoshh@shanghaitech.edu.cn

Jiashi Feng

Assistant Professor

Learning and Vision Group, Department of ECE

National University of Singapore E-mail: elefjia@nus.edu.sg